{"id":"2018_13","name":"","memoryVerse":"\"In everything [David] did he had great success, because the Lord was with him.\" â€“ 1 Samuel 18:14","dayQuestions":{"one":{"title":"FIRST DAY: Read the notes and the references.","questions":[{"id":"2018_13_1","questionText":"1. Use this space to record how you have seen God's activity during the week. (How has He provided, answered, comforted, reconciled, guided, etc.?)","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_13_2","questionText":"2. From the past week's study, what made the most significant impact to you in the notes, lecture, group sharing or personal study?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"two":{"title":"SECOND DAY: Read 1 Samuel 21 and Psalm 34.\nDavid escaped from King Saul and acknowledged God's provision and protection.","readVerse":[{"book":"1 Samuel","verse":"21:1-999"},{"book":"Psalm","verse":"34:1-999"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_13_3","questionText":"3. What are some possible ways to interpret David's and Ahimelek's interaction? Who else was present? (See Luke 6:1-5.)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Luke","verse":"6:1-5"}]},{"id":"2018_13_4","questionText":"4. What prompted David's fear in Gath? How did David escape?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_13_5a","questionText":"5. a. What does Psalm 34 reveal about David's thinking during his circumstances and escape?","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Psalm","verse":"34:1-999"}]},{"id":"2018_13_5b","questionText":"5. b. How does Psalm 34 encourage or challenge you in your present circumstances?","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Psalm","verse":"34:1-999"}]}]},"three":{"title":"THIRD DAY: Read 1 Samuel 22 and Psalm 52.\n1 Samuel 22 contrasted Saul and David's role and response in the priests' death.","readVerse":[{"book":"1 Samuel","verse":"22:1-999"},{"book":"Psalm","verse":"52:1-999"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_13_6","questionText":"6. What do you learn about Saul from his words and actions? What warnings or lessons do you find?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_13_7","questionText":"7. What do you learn about David from his words and actions? What warnings or lessons do you find?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_13_8","questionText":"8. What does Psalm 52 reveal about David's understanding of good and evil? How does this compare with your views?","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Psalm","verse":"52:1-999"}]}]},"four":{"title":"FOURTH DAY: Read 1 Samuel 23 and Psalm 54.\nGod guided David into victory and safety.","readVerse":[{"book":"1 Samuel","verse":"23:1-999"},{"book":"Psalm","verse":"54:1-999"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_13_9","questionText":"9. With whom did David consult each time before he took any action? How does that compare with your practice?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_13_10","questionText":"10. What do you learn about God in 1 Samuel 23?","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"1 Samuel","verse":"23:1-999"}]},{"id":"2018_13_11","questionText":"11. How did God encourage and protect David? How does this encourage you to trust God's leading and direction?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_13_12","questionText":"12. What truths about God did David recall in Psalm 54? Which truths about God are most comforting to you?","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Psalm","verse":"54:1-999"}]}]},"five":{"title":"FIFTH DAY: Read 1 Samuel 24 and Psalms 57 and 142.\nDavid spared Saul's life.","readVerse":[{"book":"1 Samuel","verse":"24:1-999"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_13_13","questionText":"13. What assumptions did David's men make when they met Saul in the cave? How are we guilty of making similar assumptions today?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_13_14","questionText":"14. What reasons did David give for not killing Saul? How do David's words and actions demonstrate his deep desire to honor God?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_13_15","questionText":"15. In what situation is God inviting you to do the right yet difficult thing and to trust Him with the outcome?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_13_16","questionText":"16. According to Psalm 57 and 142 what is David's ultimate prayer? How might this change the way you pray about your circumstances?","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Psalm","verse":"57:1-999"},{"book":"Psalm","verse":"142:1-999"}]}]},"six":{"title":"SIXTH DAY: Review 1 Samuel 21-24 and Psalms 34, 52, 54, 57 and 142.","readVerse":[{"book":"1 Samuel","verse":"21:1-24:999"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_13_17","questionText":"17. God described David as a man after his own heart. How did David reflect God's character in these chapters? Which qualities will you ask God to grow in you?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_13_18","questionText":"18. Homiletics for group and administrative leaders: 1 Samuel 21-24","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"1 Samuel","verse":"21:1-24:999"}]}]}}}